ECM is activated. Initiate avoidance.
ECM 啟動 開始回避動作
We can't avoid them all.
無法完全躲開
Everyone, prepare for impact.
準備承受衝擊
(Metallic Rouge)
《金屬口紅》
Good morning, Silvia.
早安 希爾維雅
Silvia.
希爾維雅…
Right.
沒錯
That is your name, shining in silver brilliance.
那是散發白銀光輝的妳的名字
Happy birthday to you!
祝妳生日快樂
Birthday?
生日…
Just now, you were born.
就在剛剛 妳出生了
This is your world.
這裡是你們的世界
Our
我們的…
world?
世界…
Thank you for being born into this world.
謝謝妳誕生到這個世界
Your pupils are the same color
那瞳孔的顏色
as Eva's.
跟艾娃一模一樣
Red Princess is about to arrive.
赤紅公主即將抵達這裡
As you instructed.
如您指示
I have arranged the reception for Miss Rouge and others.
已安排迎接露瓊小姐一行人的到來
Be alert, Opera.
不可怠慢 歐佩拉
Although my way is somewhat rough,
雖說手段有些粗暴
I have shown mercy,
但已有斟酌力度
so they can get here safely.
我會盡力讓他們安全抵達此處
As you have heard…
如各位所聞
A new world is about to begin.
新的世界即將開始了
27-degree entry angle is excessive.
侵入角27度 太深了
We're going in like this.
就這樣衝進去
What?
咦
They've arrived.
他們到了
Honestly, I thought we would die.
真是的 還以為死定了
Judging from where the Puppetmaster parked the ship,
從操偶師停船的位置來看
we should be able to get into the plant through the maintenance hatch.
應該能從維修口進去設備裡才對
Is my brother there?
哥哥就在哪裡嗎
Let's set off now.
快出發吧
Alters and the Puppetmaster must know we're here by now.
奧塔與操偶師應該都知道我們來了
It's too dangerous to stay here.
再待在這裡太危險了
Right.
是啊
Hey, what about this child?
喂 那這孩子怎麼辦
I'll take her with me.
帶她一起走
Because she is my family.
因為她也是家人
Is that okay?
這樣沒問題嗎
Even if I hear voices, I'll make my own choice.
就算聽到聲音 我也會自己決定的
Noir.
諾瓦爾…
You must greet them carefully.
要慎重迎接他們
The world is about to be born.
世界就要誕生了
Our world.
我們的世界
Your world?
你們的世界…
I thought you once said
我記得妳有說過
that there's a mission I must complete in that world.
在那個世界裡 有我必須完成的任務
Yes, correct.
是啊 沒錯
Sometimes a mission is assigned.
任務有時是被賦予的
Not to mention, you are the son of Eva Kristella,
更不用說 身為艾娃・克利絲緹勒之子的你
so you're more obligated to finish the mission, aren't you?
更有完成這項任務的義務不是嗎
What do you know about my mom?
你又知道些母親什麼事
I was there at the time.
當時我也在場
I was with Dr. Junghardt on his Nean development team,
就在容格博士的涅安開發組裡
so I am very familiar with your mom.
所以我很瞭解令堂的大小事
As the excellent assistant of Dr. Roy Junghardt,
身為羅伊・容格哈特博士 優秀助手的令堂
your mother left a glimmer of hope for Neans.
為涅安留下了一線希望
That hope is Code Eve.
那個希望就是…CODE EVE
She then hid it
然後她將此物分別藏在了
in the bodies of nine Proto-Neans,
九位原形涅安的體內
so that one day it could be retrieved
為的就是有朝一日能將其取出
to grant freedom to all Neans.
將自由賜給所有涅安
How could anyone be so compassionate?
怎會有如此慈愛之人
Yet,
然而
that love also turned her life upside down.
那份愛意同時也顛覆了她的人生
Eva Kristella suddenly
艾娃・克利絲緹勒突然之間
disappeared from everyone's sight.
消失在所有人的面前
Her disappearance involved a secret
她的失蹤牽涉著一個秘密
that cannot be shared with others.
是無法與人分享的心意
Right.
沒錯
A secret love that she can't tell anyone.
是無法向任何人訴說的 秘密之戀
Who is that object
她那秘密戀情的對象
of her secret love?
究竟是何方神聖呢
Was it someone with a close-knit family?
是擁有親密家庭之人嗎
Was it someone of unequal status?
是身分不對等的對象嗎
No.
不
Maybe it's not a person at all.
或許那個對象 根本就不是人也說不定
Gene.
吉恩…
My beloved child.
我心愛的孩子啊
Let me tell you now.
我現在就告訴你吧
Your r-real father is…
你真正的…真正的父親是…
You should stop now.
差不多就夠了
I'm having a good time.
我玩得正起勁呢
What a terrible show.
還真是拙劣的短劇
Is that so?
是這樣嗎
All the world is a stage,
整個世界就是一個舞台
like a puppet show run by invisible hands.
就如同被隱形之手所操弄的 人偶劇一般
Your mother wanted to sever
妳的母親想要斬斷
the strings manipulating Neans, known as Asimov Code.
那條操弄涅安 名為"阿茲莫夫代碼"的絲線
For this,
為此
she created Rouge Redstar who held the final key to decoding Code Eve
她才催生了藏有解讀CODE EVE 最後關鍵的露瓊・雷德斯塔
and hid her away.
並將她藏了起來
But,
但是
as her child, you used Rouge
身為她的孩子的你卻利用露瓊
to kill the Immortal Nine.
想將不朽九人葬身於黑暗之中
I don't deny it.
我不否認
What? Why?
怎麼會 為什麼
If you communicated with us properly, it wouldn't have…
如果能跟我們好好溝通的話 也不至於…
He did that.
溝通過了
What?
咦
I have talked to him.
我有…跟他談過了
Gene said he wants to create a world where humans and Neans coexist.
吉恩說想成就一個 人類與涅安共存的世界
For this, he joined the Aletheia.
為此 他才會加入真理部
However, I cannot trust humans.
然而 我無法相信人類
The corrupt bureaucracy
腐敗的官僚組織
will one day devour his ideals
終有一天會吞噬他的理想
and destroy him.
將他消滅殆盡
And…
而且…
You said you didn't have time for me
妳說沒那個時間等我
and killed my father.
然後就將父親給殺了
It's Silvia who killed my father…
是希爾維雅…將爸爸給…
Junghardt knew too much about us.
容格知道太多我們的事了
Then,
於是呢
she ordered me to monitor him.
她就命令我去監視他
But if it's just monitoring, there's no need for me to do it.
但倘若只是要監視 根本不需要我出馬吧
There's still no news from Venus.
現在依然沒有金星的任何消息
It's assumed that all plant systems on Venus are under the control of Alters.
可以認為金星上所有設備的系統 都已落入了奧塔的掌控之中
What is the status of all fleets now?
現在所有艦隊的狀況如何
JUPITER We cannot dispatch the main fleet from asteroid belt.
(木星) 小行星帶上的基幹艦隊無法行動
However,
但是
6th Space Corps on the moon can be deployed.
在月面的第6宙兵團可以進行備戰
Wait.
請等一下
If your attack
要是你們的攻擊
stops or destroys the black reactor containing micro black holes,
讓內藏小型黑洞的黑色反應爐 停止或是損毀的話
it will cause the entire Venus to collapse.
將會導致整個金星崩潰
At best, it would derail it from its current trajectory.
就算沒有也會讓其脫離現有軌道
I think
我想…
this is unavoidable.
這應該是避無可避的吧
Fortunately, our agents have now infiltrated Venus
幸好我們的特務現在潛入了金星
and are on a mission.
正在進行任務
Deputy Minister,
次官
can we leave the matter to them first?
可以先將事情交給他們處理嗎
I heard your former subordinate, Junghardt, is on Venus, right?
我聽說妳的前部下容格哈特 也在金星上不是嗎
Yes.
是的
So the chances of getting the mission done are much higher.
所以達成任務的機率也會高上不少
I wonder how many times I've heard your sweet talk.
這已經不知道是第幾次 聽信妳的花言巧語了
I haven't counted.
我沒算過
But your sweet talk isn't always a bad thing.
但妳的花言巧語通常都不是壞事
(Episode 11: Target Planet)
(11 受狙之星)
The traveling carnival is moored at the 3C Dock.
移動嘉年華是停泊在3C船塢
We can go through the wings of Dock A.
可以從A船塢的兩翼過去
Which route is the best?
哪條路才是最好的
We'll take the shortest route if we can.
可以的話要走最短路線
If we split up, we'll have to go through the weak spot of security.
分頭行動的話 就要從警戒薄弱處通過
We must proceed cautiously and quickly.
要謹慎快速前進…
Hey, I just finished.
喂 我才剛說完欸
Hey.
喂
Ash, Cyan.
亞許 希安
Damn.
可惡
We can meet at the carnival ship.
我們可以在嘉年華船會合
O-Okay.
好…好的
Where's my sister?
姊姊呢
Let's go, Cyan.
我們走吧 希安
Let's race with Rouge to see who gets to the finish line first.
來跟露瓊賽跑 看誰會先跑到終點
Hmm, I see.
嗯 我知道了
Ready. Go.
預備 開始
As you instructed,
遵照指示
I have separated them.
將他們分隔開來了
Miss Rouge and Deity Officer are taking the west wing route.
露瓊小姐與神祇官走西翼路線
The Detective of Ochrona, Cyan and Jet Black Noir
而東翼路線則是守護局探員 希安
are taking the east wing route.
以及漆黑的諾瓦爾先生
I know exactly what you are thinking.
我很清楚你在想什麼
Do as you please.
隨你去做吧
Sorry.
抱歉
Are you going to return Noir's Id to him and fight him head-to-head?
將諾瓦爾的伊德還他 堂堂正正一決勝負嗎
It's really moving.
還真是戲劇化
I am the same as Rouge.
我也和露瓊一樣
My hands are already stained with the blood of my kin.
雙手早已沾滿同胞的鮮血
And yet you're here with me without complaining.
但你還是毫無怨言地 跟我走到了現在
I will definitely come back
我一定會回來的
for the world where you exist.
為了這個有妳存在的世界
Miss Rouge and Deity Officer have entered the west wing B6.
露瓊小姐與神祇官 已進入西翼B6地區
Go ahead.
去吧
Kill the Deity Officer.
把神祇官殺掉
Do you have anything to say to your sister?
你有什麼話要跟妹妹說嗎
Please tell her to kill the man in front of her.
請幫我傳達"殺死面前這個男人"
I'll tell her you love her very much.
我會告訴她你很愛她
Rouge.
露瓊
I think
果然…
Cyan has to stay with me.
希安還是得跟我待在一起才行…
We need to go to the carnival ship first.
現在要以前往嘉年華船為重
But if I leave her alone,
可是 要是放著她不管
she will definitely mess things up.
她肯定又會亂來的
If she really does, then the other one will be doomed.
真讓她亂來的話 那對方就死定了
After all, she is Cyan.
她可是希安呢
Indeed.
的確
The Visitor made me into a Nean who could make reasonable judgments.
我是來訪者為了做出合理判斷 所製造出來的
Everything I say is correct.
我說的話都是正確的
So don't worry.
所以不用擔心啦
If the result is good, then is it considered a reasonable judgment?
結果好就好是算是合理判斷嗎
But didn't it all work out in the end?
最後不是都搞定了嗎
Oh my.
真是的
Even if you do use Code Eve to create a new world,
就算真的利用CODE EVE 開啟了新的大門
it doesn't mean that all Neans will follow you like Grauphon.
也不代表所有的涅安 會像格勞芬一樣跟隨妳
In order to provide the necessary labor on this planet,
這顆星球上 為了提供應有的勞動力
there are plants of Neans and Nectars.
設有涅安以及涅克托的製造工廠
All existing materials
現存的所有物資
can be used to produce Neans for decades to come.
可供今後數十年不斷生產涅安
Even if not all Neans will follow me,
就算所有涅安不會歸順於我
I can keep producing more Neans here.
我也能在這裡繼續生產更多同志
I can just have them join the fight.
參與戰鬥
That's proof of our existence.
那就是我們生存的証明
This is not just a world of humans,
這裡並不是只屬於人類的世界
but also a world of Neans.
也同時是我們涅安的世界
So…
所以…
This will only serve to benefit the Usurpers.
這麼做只會便宜了篡奪者
What's that called?
那句話叫什麼呢
Profit at other's expense?
漁翁之利嗎
Isn't that interesting?
這不是很有意思嗎
I'll make them regret it if they want to mess with me.
若是這樣 我會讓他們後悔的
Aerkos.
亞格斯
Take him back to the room.
帶他回去房間
Me?
咦 我嗎
Got it.
瞭解
After arriving at the carnival ship,
抵達嘉年華船後
we need to find Code Eve's analysis machine first.
要先找到CODE EVE的分析機
Don't you look for Gene?
不用找吉恩嗎
My brother's wish is to stop Silvia and others,
哥哥的願望是阻止希爾維雅他們
and safeguard the freedom of humans and the Neans.
並且守護人類與涅安的自由
I want to fulfill his wish.
我要實現他的心願
I see.
這樣啊
You look determined.
妳的表情不錯嘛
I'm flattered.
不敢當
Eva.
艾娃…
Hey, are you okay?
喂 你還行嗎
Noid.
諾伊德
Perhaps we will meet soon.
或許我們很快就會相見了
I have made my choice.
我決定要自己做出選擇
I want to support my sister.
我要成為姊姊的助力
I will protect you and Eden.
我會保護叔叔還有伊甸
Because you're special to me.
因為你們都是我的他人
What?
什麼?
Am I wrong?
咦 不對嗎
Then who is special to you?
是什麼的他人嗎
I don't quite understand,
雖然聽不太懂
but we are relying on you.
但我們就靠妳了
We are almost there.
就快到了
Just hang in there.
再咬牙撐一下
Okay.
好…
So you wanted to talk with us.
原來你有打算要跟我們談啊
I still remember
我還記得…
you and I caught bugs by the lake.
你在湖邊抓到蟲子的模樣
We found a bug we hadn't seen before.
當時我找到了沒看過的蟲子呢
You all are my family.
你們都是我的家人
That's why I dream of a world where humans and Neans live in peace.
所以我才會夢想著 人類與涅安和平共處的世界
But, to realize this dream,
然而你卻為了實現這個夢想
you ordered that girl to kill our kin?
命令那個女孩殺害自己的同胞嗎
You and Silvia are exactly alike.
你跟希爾維雅根本一模一樣
Whether humans or Neans, obsessing too much
只要太過為人類或是涅安著想的話
makes one foolish.
大多都會成為這種笨蛋呢
Yes.
是啊…
There may be other ways to do it.
或許會有其他做法也不一定
But,
不過…
I don't hate such fools.
我並不討厭這種笨蛋
Cyan.
希安
My daughter born at the carnival.
誕生於嘉年華的女兒啊
I heard the voice.
我聽到聲音了
Didn't you make a promise to your sister?
妳不是跟姊姊說好了嗎
You said that even if you heard it, you could make your own choice.
說就算聽到聲音 也能自己做出決定
Come here, Cyan.
過來 希安
Come to the carnival.
過來嘉年華
You can't lose to that voice.
不能輸給那個聲音
I have to go.
我得過去…
-Come on! -I have to go.
-加油啊 -我得過去…
-You are a strong child.
-妳是堅強的孩子
Cyan.
希安
Ash, you go stop Cyan.
亞許 去阻止希安
What?
咦
You're the only one who can stop her now.
現在能阻止她的人 就只有妳了
And I think it's me he wants to talk to.
而且他想找的人 應該是我
Go ahead, human.
去吧 人類
I'll wait for you at the destination.
我在終點等你
You're back, Cyan.
妳回來啦 希安
My beloved daughter.
我心愛的女兒
Masked father.
戴面具的爸爸
That voice wasn't you?
那個聲音不是你對吧
No.
不
That was indeed me.
是我沒錯
He…
他是…
Alright.
好了
This is the last show.
這是最後的表演了
Don't touch that girl.
不准碰那個女孩
From now on, you will play a new role.
從現在起 妳將要扮演新的角色
A new stage
新的舞台
and a new life are about to begin.
以及新的人生 即將開演
I'm so confused
我也真是老糊塗了
that I was tricked by you.
居然被玩弄在股掌之間
Damn.
可惡
Have Cyan and others arrived yet?
希安他們是不是已經到了啊
No matter what,
可能到了 也可能還沒到
we have no time to stop.
總之我們沒時間停下來
This way.
往這邊
Where are we going now?
我們現在是往哪裡前進
We're heading to the black reactor.
去黑色反應爐
This way will be quicker.
走這裡會比較快
Black…
黑色…
What is that?
那是什麼
A generator that uses micro black holes to generate power.
是利用小型黑洞產生能量的發電機
Hurry up.
動作快
Okay.
喔
I have to stop Silvia and others.
一定要組止希爾維雅他們才行
If I fail,
要是失敗的話…
I will again…
我就會又…
Rouge.
露瓊
You're safe and sound.
妳平安無事啊
Is this what they call "asking for trouble"?
這就是所謂的"異想天開"嗎
I really don't understand.
真是難以理解
Don't worry.
放心吧
Your misfortunate son
你那身為忌子的兒子
is still alive.
現在還活著
Give Gene back to me.
把吉恩還來